The SQL Language has a few different elements,
تتضمن لغة SQL بضعة عناصر مختلفة،
the most basic of which is a statement.
والأكثر أساسية من بينها هو العبارة.
Think of a statement as simply a piece of correctly written SQL code.
فكِّروا في العبارة على أنها ببساطة قطعة من كود SQL مكتوب بشكل صحيح.
Statements tell the database what you'd like to do with the data.
تأمر العبارات قاعدة البيانات بما تريدون فعله بالبيانات.
The CREATE statement for example,
مثلًا عبارة CREATE
is how you make a new table in the database.
هي الكيفية التي تنشئون بها جدولًا جديدًا في قاعدة البيانات.
The DROP TABLE statement is how you remove a table from the database.
عبارة DROP TABLE هي الكيفية التي تحذفون بها جدولًا من قاعدة البيانات.
In this lesson, we'll focus on the SELECT statement,
في هذا الدرس سوف نركِّز على عبارة SELECT،
which allows you to read data and display it.
والتي تتيح لنا قراءة البيانات وعرضها.
SELECT statements are commonly referred to as queries.
عادةً ما يُشار إلى عبارات SELECT على أنها استفسارات.
There are a few other types of statements that SQL understands.
هناك بضعة أنواع أخرى من العبارات تفهمها لغة SQL.
They all have different functions,
جميع هذه الأنواع لها دوال مختلفة،
most of which relate to the creation and removal of data.
يرتبط معظمها بإنشاء البيانات وحذفها.
Eventually, you'll learn how to do that,
أخيرًا، ستتعلمون كيف تفعلون ذلك؛
but the majority of analytical work doesn't involve adding,
لكن أغلب العمل التحليلي لا يتضمن إضافة
removing, or modifying data within a database.
أو حذف أو تعديل البيانات داخل قاعدة بيانات،
It requires reading data and manipulating it,
بل يتطلب قراءة البيانات ومعالجتها
but only occasionally updating the underlying source.
لكن بما يقتصر فقط على تحديث المصدر الكامن من حين إلى آخر.